brilliantmaps.com 2019-06-14

# Privacy Policy For BrilliantMaps.com – Brilliant Maps

This privacy policy has been compiled by BrilliantMaps.com (owned by Brilliant British Ltd, Company number 10490224 (Registered in England and Wales), Registered office address: 2nd Floor 167-169 Great Portland Street, London, United Kingdom, W1W 5PF.) to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally identifiable information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in UK privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. 

Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website.

**Processing Data Under The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)**

Our legal basis of processing data is **legitimate interest.** We are primarily an informational website and while technically a data controller we process minimal amounts of personal data and only use standard third-party tools. 

In plain English here are the tools and platforms we use, why we use them and how you can manage your data on them. If you would like to block access to these tools, not just on our site, but across the web, we recommend looking at a solution such as [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/).

  * **Google Adsense:** We use Google Adsense to help pay for the running of this website. We have chosen to opt-out of showing personalised ads, third party ads and ads from Google certified ad networks. Although we have opted-out of showing third party ads you may also want to read their guide to [Opt out of seeing personalised ads here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en-GB).
  * **Google Analytics:** This is used to track website usage in aggregate. We do not use it to track individual users. Here are the key settings we are currently using: Remarketing: OFF; Advertising Reporting Features: OFF; User and event data retention: Set to expire after 14 months (shortest option offered); Reset on new activity: ON; User-ID: OFF; Accepted GDPR Data Processing Amendment. Google currently offers an Analytics [opt-out here](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en). 
  * **Google Custom Search Engine:** We use this to help users search our site, and as a way of generating a little extra revenue since we get paid if you click on any ads while searching.
  * **Amazon Associates:** At the bottom of every post you’ll find recommend related products from Amazon. We also include links to many products on Amazon in our articles. These are both done to help support our site. When you buy something on Amazon after visiting one of these links we get paid a small commission and it doesn’t come with any extra cost to you, so win-win. To learn more about how Amazon tracks you, please see their [privacy policy here](https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=502584).
  * **Facebook Social Graph:** This helps make it easier to share our content on Facebook and shows how often content has been shared on Facebook. See Facebook’s [Data Page](https://www.facebook.com/help/1701730696756992/?helpref=hc_fnav) for more on how they use your data.
  * **Cookie Consent:** This is used to inform users that we use cookies and other third party tools and platforms. It is provided by Silktide and you can [learn more here](https://cookieconsent.insites.com/).
  * **SumoMe:** This is used by us to help users subscribe to our newsletter. You can learn more about their [privacy policy here](https://help.sumo.com/hc/en-us/articles/218958727-Privacy-Policy).
  * **Mailchimp:** We use Mailchimp to send our periodic newsletter and they store your e-mail address. The newsletter is completely voluntary to join, primarily informational (although may include up to 2 ads per send) and double opt-in. Each newsletter always has an unsubscribe link in the footer. You can see MailChimp’s [Privacy Policy here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).
  * **StudioPress:** They host our website and may have logs about all visitors to this site, although we do not have direct access to them. You can learn more about the data they may have on their [privacy policy](https://www.studiopress.com/privacy-policy/).
  * **Social Media Sharing:** In addition to Facebook Social Graph we also have G+ and Twitter sharing buttons on our site to help make it easier to share our content on those platforms. You can see [G+ privacy policy here](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and Twitter’s [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy) here.
  * **Affiliate/external links:** We may occasionally include affiliate links besides those to Amazon to help support the site. Generally speaking we will make note of these either in the article itself or the footer of the article. Any sort of tracking only occurs if you click on an external link. If you’re concerned about this, the simplest option is to not click on external links from our website.

Finally, as noted above, we occasionally send out a newsletter to people who’ve opted-in to our newsletter. All subscribers have consented to receive it via a double opt-in process and can unsubscribe at any point. The newsletter is primarily non-commercial (although may contain 1-2 ads to offset the cost of sending) All e-mail addresses are stored with MailChimp as noted above. 

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our website?**

We do not collect any personal information directly, but some information may be collected by one or more of the tools or platforms above. The exception is your e-mail address if you want opt-in to receive our newsletter. 

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to our newsletter. Other information may be collected as you navigate around the site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you sign up for our newsletter, or surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

  * To improve our website in order to better serve you.
  * To send periodic emails if you join our newsletter.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards. We use an SSL certificate. We only provide articles and information and do not process any sort of payment data or other sensitive information.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. 

They are also used to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

**We use cookies to:**

  * Keep track of advertisements.
  * Compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future.
  * We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer, Chrome, Firefox, etc.) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

If you disable cookies off, some features will be disabled. It won’t affect the users experience that make your site experience more efficient and some of our services will not function properly.

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety. 

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles. They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users. <https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en>

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad settings](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences) and content network privacy policy.

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website. 

**Opting out:**

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the [Google Ad Settings page](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences). Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

CalOPPA is the first state law in the nation to require commercial websites and online services to post a privacy policy. The law’s reach stretches well beyond California to require a person or company in the United States (and conceivably the world) that operates websites collecting personally identifiable information from California consumers to post a conspicuous privacy policy on its website stating exactly the information being collected and those individuals with whom it is being shared, and to comply with this policy. – See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

**According to CalOPPA we agree to the following:**

Users can visit our site anonymously. Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website. Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes:

  * On our Privacy Policy Page

Users are able to change their personal information:

  * By emailing us

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place. 

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

It’s also important to note that we do not allow third party behavioral tracking.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

When it comes to the collection of personal information from children under 13, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) puts parents in control. The Federal Trade Commission, the nation’s consumer protection agency, enforces the COPPA Rule, which spells out what operators of websites and online services must do to protect children’s privacy and safety online.

We do not specifically market to children under 13 and this website is aimed at an audience that is 18+.

**CAN SPAM Act**

The CAN-SPAM Act is a law that sets the rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to have emails stopped from being sent to them, and spells out tough penalties for violations.

**We collect your email address in order to:**

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.
  * Market to our mailing list

**To be accordance with CANSPAM we agree to the following:**

  * NOT use false, or misleading subjects or email addresses
  * Identify the message as an advertisement in some reasonable way
  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters
  * Monitor third party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.
  * Honor opt-out/unsubscribe requests quickly
  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email

**  
If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, you can** Follow the instructions at the bottom of each email. and we will promptly remove you from **ALL** correspondence.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may [contact us here](https://brilliantmaps.com/contact/).
